<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>katie&#39;s journal</title>
    <description>Thoughts about college life, computer science, artificial intelligence and philosophy
</description>
    <link>katiebui.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="katiebui.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 20:53:06 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 20:53:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why you can&#39;t just seem to &quot;just do it&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Underneath my bed are a pair of Nike shoes, and in my drawer are some Nike running shorts with a Nike sports bra.  You’d think that my attraction to this brand has to do with my values–“just do it”–being parallel to how they market themselves, but I think it’s something a bit more subtle: I want my values to be parallel to that powerful little aphorism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would I know if my values actually are in line with Nike’s?  In the Nike commercials they portray athletes running into things (the water, the track, the soccer field), getting tired, and winning things.  More often than not, they are people who have already achieved greatness.  If you go to Nike’s website, their models have bodies that, err, embody the signs of greatness that they hold to the light.  Their sculpted abs, fierce gazes, and statuesque action poses are visible and visceral signs of progress that appear regardless of who is watching, giving feedback or cheering from the sidelines.  So maybe I’d know if greatness has been achieved if I’ve struggled, pushed through, and grown some muscles.  That’s how I’d know if I’ve “just done it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then why won’t I do the things I said I’d do?  Why won’t I dig into that open-source project, why won’t I take up hip hop dance lessons again, why won’t I call up that one friend whom I haven’t seen since high school, why won’t I learn that new language, why won’t I study for my finals like I should be doing right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Pink’s Drive, Charles Duhigg’s The Power of Habit, and Malcolm Gladwell’s Outliers say that I’ve basically got all the psychological, biological and practical resources to do the shit I said I was gonna do: a supportive community (going to a university), a healthy mind and body, and internet access to basically the collective human knowledge of the world.  So why aren’t I just doing it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, I think the “it” part of “just do it” is worthy of discussion.  The “do”-ing part seems to be pretty simple; you can probably condense the physical actions needed to actually do any of my current goals listed about into a recipe-like list of directions.  The “it” part is kind of ambiguous: what does “digging into that open-source project” even mean to me?  What does “calling up a friend” mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our minds will readily supply the answer.  “Well, Katie, go Google ‘open-source development’ and go see for yourself!”  or “It means Facebook messaging them with some sort of friendly ‘Long time no see’ greeting and then inviting them to have a coffee.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then our bodies will have usually some sort of funky reaction to that.  For me, I get this feeling like a pristine, white sheet of paper has been crumpled up in my chest.  I get cringe-y.  I also get this angel-demon hybrid that pops up on my shoulder that says, “Ah, but if you don’t, you’re a coward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that quick little reaction, I do one of three things: I do it to its completion (about 10% of the time), I attempt doing it and then drop it within ten minutes (about 40% of the time) or I open up a tab to ebay.com or fanfiction, thinking that I might as well enjoy myself a bit before embarking on doing the first option, and then end up doing something else completely different (about 50% of the time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you might think, “Ah, perhaps this post is about increasing that 10% of the time she actually executes her vision, and how I might be able to.”  No, actually–I’m writing about vision is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I, and many people of my generation, have lived life so far, in two different versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I was born in the 90s in San Jose, CA, in the heart of Silicon Valley.  My dad was an engineer, my mom a nurse, and we are a pretty wealthy family.  I&#39;d like to keep life that way, especially in such an awesome, dynamic place like the Bay Area, so I really don&#39;t see why I shouldn&#39;t try to aim for a job at Google or Apple.  I mean, I can do it--I know what it&#39;s like to grind at something to get what I&#39;ve wanted, whether it be a super tough boss battle in a video game, an A, saving up for my phone, whatever.  After all, I&#39;d be doing important work with my major, so I think that&#39;s good for my life.  And I&#39;d get a nice 6-figure salary and meet well-informed, ambitious people like me whom I could build my life around.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I was born.  Then my parents took care of me.  Had some good times, had some bad, but for the most part I took for granted my good times, and only oversaw the bad times without dealing directly with the mess itself (e.g. being the recipient/victim of a layoff, lawsuit, divorce, or crime).  A lot of people said that doing X was good, so I did that, because there didn&#39;t seem to be a reason to do the other way.  There are many ways to go about doing X (i.e. getting a high-paying job, a stable life with a house and family, accomplishing good work in my community) and they all are theoretically sound.  I spend a lot of time trying to do X and other good things that are related to X.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference?  The first sounds like an animated narrative, like a breath of humanity has been blown onto it.  The second sounds more detached, even Stoic.  Both of these are “right” in their own ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is a story that we usually tell ourselves.  It’s our natural caffeine, our motivations and logical tactics for us to envelop ourselves in a world where there’s shit to be done, there’s problems to solve, and our existence has a purpose in this huge machine we’re all born into.  There’s an almost video-gamish aspect to it: choose your calling, choose the skills you’ll hone, choose the quests to fulfill and then gather companionship with your fellow players.  Hey, video games are fun.  It’s fun to think of life this way and it’s easier to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second isn’t really a story; it’s more like a sequence of events that our bodies have actually lived and experience.  While it seems really simplified, that is likely how our bodies interpret our lives.  It doesn’t particularly recall certain moments in the past and cherish them in the way our minds do because it lives in the sliver-thin moments of present time.  And each of those moments I was living my awesome plans in my head, I was making my body (well, myself) suffer through doing coding assignments at 4 am, going to club meetings half-asleep, meeting friends in the middle of midterms and cutting the time short because we’re both so goddamn busy, and somehow getting up every morning in dedication to these voices in my head telling me I should just keep doing “it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we arrive to trying to answer the question, “What is this ‘it’?”  Where did I get the idea that I should ever accomplish these “it”s?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I approved and agreed to these goals and plans.  They are good for my life.  Why wouldn’t I trust the myriad of experts whose articles I’ve been reading, or my classmates who are smarter than me, or even my own eyes of seeing what it’s like having money, being surrounded by certain people, doing certain kinds of work?  Yo, it’s difficult to say that my half-sister, who now makes probably $200K+ in a biomedical device company and spends time Yelping with her sharp-minded and fun-loving friends and co-workers, isn’t living a good life.  Hey, I want a good life, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s this movie named Surrogate about a society where people have robots live their lives out for them.  While it’s kind of ridiculous and not even a really good movie, our society is already sort of like that.  We have all these digital and made up representations of what our lives could be, these virtual carrots raining down in our visions, and we are trained to think that getting these carrots is a way of validating ourselves and living our lives.
The only difference lies in who does the execution: in the movie, there are cold, metallic contraptions doing so, in real life, there are cold hearts–once warm and alive–mechanically doing the work that other people keep telling us to do.  And the real persons in ourselves are sitting back, hoping to reap the joys that were promised to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when we hear “just do it,” who is the one doing it?  Is it our minds, sitting up in their high chairs?  Or is it our bodies, the actual vehicles of bone and flesh that type the code, that stay up during the late nights, that glue their eyes to the books, that anchor themselves to chairs for ten or so hours a day despite not having been sculpted by evolution to do so?  And now our minds have even more plans that need to be realized, which need more nights of staying up, more professors to please, more employers to reach out to, more hours of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we end up doing it anyway because we begin hating ourselves if we don’t.  We call ourselves names that other people have called us or called others when they don’t behave the way they want.  My demons call me a coward, they say that I’m weak, they threaten to drag the rest of my life down if I don’t do X–not for them of course, but for “my own benefit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well.  No wonder I didn’t “just do it.”  I–truly, I–never really had wanted to.  I’ve been so out of touch with what I actually want.  No one taught me fucking ask myself and indulge.  And don’t get me wrong, I don’t just want to lay around all day eating potato chips and having sex.  I need a rest.  And I need to figure out what I actually want, which is one thing that no one, or no school, or no inspirational speaker has ever taught me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s because the answers are inside of me or, with enough experiences and painful lessons, they will be inside me.  I can help figure out these answers by seeing how others did for themselves, i.e. reading the biographies of great people who managed to blend their desires and goals into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if “just do it” is still a good motto to have for me.  Maybe it works once I find those “it”s.  And I will, because I know I’m brave enough to ask myself what they are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>katiebui.com/2016/03/14/why-you-just-cant-seem-to-do-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">katiebui.com/2016/03/14/why-you-just-cant-seem-to-do-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>values</category>
        
        <category>goals</category>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>March 2016 Media Roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Books read&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Women, Food, and God, by Geneen Roth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Books reading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Obstacle is the Way, by Ryan Holliday&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Meaning of it All, by Richard Feynman&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Power of Now, by Eckhart Tolle&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Stuff Matters, by Mark Miodownik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cool articles read and videos watched&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lesswrong.com/lw/dr9/game_theory_as_a_dark_art/&quot;&gt;Game Theory As a Dark Art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://phys.org/news/2016-02-scientists-efficiency-water-splitting-half-reaction.html&quot;&gt;Scientists achieve perfect efficiency for water splitting half-reaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2015/jan/20/barack-obama/obama-claims-us-has-doubled-production-clean-energ/&quot;&gt;Obama claims U.S. has doubled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://b-gat.es/1Ql32K9&quot;&gt;Bill Gates&#39; Annual Letter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y0WIE-ySC7c&quot;&gt;A Female eSports Champion Speaks Out About Harassment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bjYhmX_OUQQ&quot;&gt;What happens when you dare expert hackers to hack you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/forbes/welcome/#1b53c4967a29&quot;&gt;Can these panties disrupt the $15 billion feminine hygiene market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DnpO_RTSNmQ&quot;&gt;Last Week Tonight with John Oliver: Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://discovermagazine.com/1987/may/02-the-worst-mistake-in-the-history-of-the-human-race&quot;&gt;The worst mistake in the history of the human race (a criticism of agriculture)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/items/2009/09/23.html&quot;&gt;The Duct Tape Programmer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/gallery/34335649/Science-Kombat&quot;&gt;Science Kombat animations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/28/upshot/what-its-really-like-to-risk-it-all-in-silicon-valley.html?_r=1&quot;&gt;What it&#39;s really like to risk it all in Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GgNsmW_bAKI&quot;&gt;The Better Angels of Our Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/hackathon-highlights/the-douche-bag-guide-to-winning-every-hackathon-943096ba8cb#.8ewmm4g4t&quot;&gt;The Douche-Bag Guide to Winning Every Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s86-Z-CbaHA&quot;&gt;Vsauce&#39;s take on the Banach-Tarski Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U3Of-jF1nWo&quot;&gt;Facebook account takeover bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-does-it-feel-like-to-be-fired-from-Facebook&quot;&gt;What does it feel like to be kicked out of Facebook?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2016/03/07/4chan-creator-joins-google-team/&quot;&gt;Google hires of the founder of lawless site 4chan to help revive Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gq.com/story/unexpected-jeff-goldblum?mbid=red_23S_chevy&quot;&gt;Jeff Goldblum wants you to consider growing younger instead of older&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-economy-is-better-why-dont-voters-believe-it/&quot;&gt;The economy is better -- why don&#39;t voters believe it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slatestarcodex.com/2014/07/30/meditations-on-moloch/&quot;&gt;Meditations on Moloch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/reshma_saujani_teach_girls_bravery_not_perfection?utm_campaign=social&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=facebook.com&amp;amp;utm_content=talk&amp;amp;utm_term=education&quot;&gt;Teach girls bravery, not perfection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2014-04-23/the-dumb-way-we-board-airplanes-remains-impervious-to-good-data&quot;&gt;The dumb way we board airplanes remains impervious to good data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2016/03/sadness-beauty-watching-googles-ai-play-go/&quot;&gt;The sadness and beauty of watching Google&#39;s AI play Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/vlogbrothers/videos&quot;&gt;Why the word &quot;millenial&quot; makes me cringe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/2016-Annual-Letter-Recap?WT.mc_id=20160315230300_AL2016_BG-FB&amp;amp;WT.tsrc=BGFB&amp;amp;linkId=2232233?&quot;&gt;Bill Gates&#39; visit to Metropolis reflection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Other things I looked at and discovered&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Soylent and its benefits&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Leo gets the Oscar&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Analyzing Kendrick Lamar lyrics&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Trump (of course)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lots of relationship advice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Makeup--J.One Jelly Pack and Glossier&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;TONS of Super Smash Bros. gameplay&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lots of internship opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pokemon Showdown&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;MEAN stack vs. Meteor.js vs. Django&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Homework-related things... C, Unix, and machine learning methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… and a ton of Elliott Hulse videos, of course.  ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>katiebui.com/2016/03/14/March-MEdia-Roundup-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">katiebui.com/2016/03/14/March-MEdia-Roundup-2016.html</guid>
        
        <category>media</category>
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
        <category>collection</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Duckvan Beta Testing Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month or two ago, there was this post in a Facebook group that asked its members if they wanted to be beta testers for their new subscription service, Duckvan.  It’s basically a strong, challenging dose of exoticism, or as Duckvan puts it on their website, “your monthly box of WTF.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to ever coming across this concept, I’ve always been a bit of an adventurous eater, so I definitely was pumped when I got the package in the mail!  My boyfriend, who doesn’t stray far from the usual American fare, was dragged along with taste-testing everything out.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Packaging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some initial reactions:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&quot;Wow, clean lines and fresh colors.  Nice.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&quot;It&#39;s also kind of speckle-y... I suppose the printing process wasn&#39;t too solid.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&quot;What a cute icon, lol.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Fresh&quot; is the word that comes to mind when I look at the packaging.  The light blue, playful yellow and white sans-serif font motif going on makes me feel kind of excited to venture into some weird food territory.  It lends a sort of safe, yet energetic mood for what I&#39;m about to experiment with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After figuring out how to open the thing--it&#39;s one of those tapeless, folded cardboard boxes that adds a second or two in the unboxing process--here it is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haha, the green shredded stuff looks like grass.  My boyfriend asked, &quot;Are those dollar bills?!&quot;  Indeed, it looked like shredded dollar bills, but I&#39;m pretty sure they&#39;re not.  They don&#39;t feel or smell like them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pretty glad this was included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/04.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s nice to know what you&#39;re eating.  I loved reading the blurbs; they do a pretty good job of building the anticipatory tension that goes with eating this stuff.  At the same time, I think it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; seems to target already-adventurous eaters.  Only an idiot like me would find ingredients for hand grenades and welding steel suitable for putting into my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;ve actually had almost everything on the list, except for the Salsaghetti.  I was actually kind of scared of eating that one, LOL.  It reminds me of the packaging of really cheap snacks in convenience stores that usually tasted like crap.  For perspective, I&#39;m including my boyfriend&#39;s thoughts on these things, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/045.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/05.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, let&#39;s dig in.  First up is the ghost pepper popcorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ghost Pepper Popcorn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/10.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon microwaving this throat-killer, the bag popped like any other microwaved popcorn and even smelled like it too.  The main difference came when actually inhaling the odor of the ghost pepper popcorn--it &lt;em&gt;hurt&lt;/em&gt;.  Like, it literally stung my throat to just sniff the thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My boyfriend&#39;s friends also happened to be over and we decided to prank him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
BF: Hey, want some popcorn?
&lt;br /&gt;
Friend: (Pause) Sure...
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Takes fistfull of popcorn and eats it&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Friend:  Alright, what&#39;d you do to it?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the poor guy had to be rushed over to the kitchen to douse his mouth with water.  For the next hour or so, everybody was coughing because the spiciness of the pepper permeated the entire apartment... Haha, we had to open all the doors and turn on the AC for about an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole bag still hasn&#39;t been finished; it&#39;s just so spicy.  I gained some masochistic pleasure from eating it though.  My boyfriend&#39;s Indian roommate on the other hand: &quot;Just needs more butter.&quot;

&lt;h3&gt;Wasabi Kit-Kat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was personally disappointed; it didn&#39;t have any wasabi taste.  My boyfriend&#39;s thought: &quot;Oh good, it tastes normal!&quot;  I did have a wasabi kit kat before, though, and it *did* taste like wasabi.  Not sure why these kit kats ended up tasting like milk-flavored kat kats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Salmiakki&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had very strong Swedish licorice before and I liked it, so I was mostly looking forward to my boyfriend&#39;s reactions, hahaha.  I can confirm that this licorice was the real deal--super salty, alkaline, and packed with its signature anise flavor.  The softer variant might be better on the teeth, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My boyfriend wasn&#39;t a huge fan of this one.  The al-dente chewiness lingered for too long for him to like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Durian candy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in a Vietnamese family, I was no stranger to durian.  In fact it&#39;s actually my favorite fruit!  So when I unwrapped the candy and popped it into my mouth, I was vaulted into my land of childhood memories.  Surprisingly my boyfriend actually enjoyed it; I&#39;d totally crack open a real durian for him to try one day.  :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Salsaghetti&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this was the only candy that took me out of my comfort zone, so I took a couple of photos for this.  I mean... it&#39;s stringified gummy fruit stuff with &lt;em&gt;sauce&lt;/em&gt;.  Sauce?!  And it was meant to be emulate the spaghetti-eating experience, which should taste neither fruity nor gummy nor spicy.  Oh lord.  Well, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like a kid again opening a mini Lunchables box, what with that tiny yellow packet to rip open and smother onto my food.  Except the difference is that the food itself looks like (a) brains or (b) ground red meat.  Too bad it didn&#39;t come with a small plastic fork, though!  I had to grab a fork to spread the thing around (because lord knows I am not eating that with my fingers.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/08.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Awww yeah.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://katiebui.com/assets/duckvan/09.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POWERFUL.&lt;/strong&gt;  Wow, this was kind of like eating a watermelon-flavored spicy Warheads candy!!  The sauce added a sharp sourness to the spicy crystals embedded in the noodles.  The noodles themselves overpowered my tastebuds with Jolly-Rancheresque, artificial watermelon-y and saccharine waves of flavor.  We ended up liking it (me moreso than him), but WOW.  What an explosive way to scarf down 70 calories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the salsaghetti was, surprisingly, a novel experience that turned out well for me, I&#39;d say eating that was the most Duckvannish experience I was given.  The boyfriend liked the popcorn the most because it was &quot;fun&quot; (???).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have to say that Duckvan has a way to go for determining its target audience.  While they proclaim on their website that they&#39;re &quot;not for beginners,&quot; they should realize that the adventurous veterans like me have likely tried the snacks that they&#39;d be sending.  I definitely had fun sharing my experiences with friends who hadn&#39;t tried them, though, so perhaps that&#39;s a good place to start from marketing-wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thank the Duckvan team for sending me this epic and hilarious box of fun over to Irvine, and I really hope y&#39;all do a great job on your release!!  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>katiebui.com/2016/02/20/Duckvan-Review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">katiebui.com/2016/02/20/Duckvan-Review.html</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>humor</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2016 Resolutions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Haha, everytime I write New Year’s resolutions, I can’t find where I put it a year later so that I could reflect upon it.  Since I’ve gone to such lengths to set up this blog, hopefully it’ll be nested comfortably in permanence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;This Year&#39;s Resolutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think to make them actually doable and trackable, I should make the resulting habits or goals concrete.  Most if not all of these goals are about routinization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Eating processed sweets only once every three days&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	This problem&#39;s bad enough to warrant its own tier, lol. It&#39;s not even in a cute way, like how L from Death Note childishly eats strawberries and eclairs. Lots of money goes wasted from tossing out actual, healthy food that ends up rotting in the fridge because I&#39;d end up replacing meals with sugary cereal or cookies (sob).  An exception I&#39;m going to make, though, is fruit.  It&#39;s got vitamins and fiber!
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;To&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; verb &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; noun &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; time frame&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To read a book a month&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To cook homemade food every other day&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To tidy up my room every Sunday&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To do an algorithm problem every day&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To write something, digitally or on paper, every day&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To work on ONE personal project every day&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To watch a whole TV/anime series (up to 50 episodes) every break&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To beat a video game every quarter&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To go outside every day&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;To do something &lt;i&gt;entirely for no reason&lt;/i&gt; every day&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
		I&#39;m sure there&#39;s going to be more added to this at some point.
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Controlling my compulsiveness&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	It was not until just a couple weeks ago I realized that I tend to be pretty compulsive.  While it&#39;s done some pretty good things for me in the past--a great three-day trip to L.A. to see a concert the week before finals, for example--it&#39;s also caused me quite a bit of damage in the long-run.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;An example is buying things.  As I was growing up, my mother was (and still is) very compulsive about making huge, luxurious purchases (like buying a pair of $1500 shoes she didn&#39;t even like).  I thought it was normal, until I faced the challenges of carrying that poor habit to college.  After whittling my budget down to subsisting on rice and soy sauce a couple of times, I finally got my crap together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;What I&#39;m struggling with now is health.  I mentioned my sweet tooth above; I have an compulsiveness to substitute sweets for healthy food.  Worse yet, I love eating a lot of finger foods at once.  Man, those days where I had a giant bag of Rold Gold thins for all my meals...  What I&#39;m going to do is time myself as I&#39;m eating something.  If I&#39;m eating cereal, for instance, I have to choose a brand where the pieces are reasonably large, and then time myself to eat one piece/minute. &lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;I also find it difficult right now to focus doing just &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; thing for more than ten or fifteen minutes, unless I&#39;m relentlessly crazy about it.  In other words, I want to routinize my workflow, since it sort of resembles a fireworks show rather than the consistent glow of the sun.  The easiest way to go about this is probably to just catch myself being super unfocused or being super intense, and then correct it.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;To feel other people&#39;s emotions more strongly&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	After playing an awesome game called &lt;i&gt;Undertale&lt;/i&gt;, I realized that much of people&#39;s troubles stem from the inability to relate and communciate correctly.  As for me, I&#39;m an intensely emotional person... but mostly for things that occur in my life.  That extent of emotional-ness doesn&#39;t need to concern everybody in the world, but I do want to be able to care very deeply about others.  So what I want to do is pray for someone (not necessarily anyone I know) every day.  Maybe I could go further with this later.
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Make learning technical stuff as seamless as possible&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	It takes a lot of energy and mind-bending to understand code.  Really, I think it all comes down to being comfortable with understanding how stuff fits and works together--mechanics, and why that stuff could be expanded to other stuff that doesn&#39;t exist yet--design (maybe mathematics).
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	So every day, these are some activities that could be done to help out with that kind of thinking:
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Drawing something, like cars or buildings or cats, from every perspective (front, back, 3/4, skewed angles, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Reading and sketching how everyday objects operate (e.g. how does a toaster work?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Straight-up doing algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Assembling stuff together, like sewing clothing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, I think five for now is pretty good.  :)
Good luck to everyone this year!  I hope everyone achieves what they set out to do.  As Shia LaBouf says, “Don’t let your dreams be dreams.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>katiebui.com/2016/01/01/resolutions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">katiebui.com/2016/01/01/resolutions.html</guid>
        
        <category>resolutions</category>
        
        <category>goals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hurray, finished!! + Fixing Jekyll Problems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Holy crap, I finally have my own little home on the Internet!  I’ve built lots of websites in the past, but none with so much effort as this one.  My bed mattress probably has a dent in it from me having laid on it for like, two days straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many languages to assemble together this with Jekyll.  Along with HTML/CSS and JavaScript (which was expected), there was some impromptu YAML, Liquid, and Markdown language learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building Jekyll took about 50% the time and 80% the frustration.  Poor documentation made building Jekyll on GitHub Pages &lt;i&gt;way&lt;/i&gt; harder than it needed to be!!  Argh.  For the soul out there that landed here through Google, here are some fixes I had to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Jekyll must run on the root directory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks can deceive… this blog ran a-okay on a subdirectory under my local GitHub repository, but failed to build when pushed to GitHub.  I had my website configured like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;portfolio
|___ index.html 		(of portfolio)
|___ ... 				(other files pertaining to portfolio)
|___ ...
|___ ...
|___ jekyll blog
        |___ index.html (of blog)
        |___ ...
        |___ ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that in the _configure.yml file, GitHub Pages overrides whatever source directory you set it up as.  Then when it attempts to build your site, it will begin looking for subdirections in the &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; directory rather than from where your jekyll subdirectory is.  In my case, it was trying to find _includes.  I got this email from GitHub:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
The page build failed with the following error:

A file was included in `kb-blog/index.html` that is a symlink or does not exist in your `_includes` directory. For more information, see https://help.github.com/articles/page-build-failed-file-is-a-symlink.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What I had to do&lt;/b&gt; was make the jekyll blog’s subdirectory’s files at the same level as the portfolio’s.  So it would be organized this way instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll blog
|___ journal.html       (of blog)
|___ ...                (other files pertaining to blog)
|___ ...
|___ ...
|___ index.html         (of portfolio)
|___ ...                (other files pertaining to portfolio)
|___ ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is messy and disorganized, I know!  See the next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;DNS servers only point to baseurls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had once tried to make the structure of the website look more like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll blog
|___ index.html         (of blog)
|___ ...
|___ ...
|___ portfolio
    |___ index.html (of portfolio)
    |___ ...
    |___ ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I wanted katiebui.com to point to the index of my portfolio, not my blog.  (In other words, katiebui.com -&amp;gt; ti-lun.github.io/portfolio/index.html.)  As much as I like to write and stuff, it’s not like I’m featuring top-notch content here yet :’D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What I had to do&lt;/b&gt; was organize the website like the way I had it in the first diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Jekyll has no tagging system.. or, at least, a readily apparent one&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, right?  I just followed &lt;a href=&quot;http://vrepin.org/vr/Tagging/&quot; target=&quot;&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.  It was just adding a Ruby plugin to generate a page for each tag, and then creating a page that aggregated all the blog’s tags using Liquid.  Yet there was a wrinkle here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;GitHub Pages doesn&#39;t support Ruby plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, figuring out that &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; was the issue involved an hour or two of confusion and testing of will.  The problem manifested into this really odd paranoia of, “Why aren’t the tag pages being generated?!”  After all, the locally-generated Jekyll blog was working perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here were some symptoms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;My GitHub showed that the Jekyll blog&#39;s _site subdirectory was uploaded, along with the tag subdirectory (its child).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;None of the tag folder&#39;s subdirectories were accessible in the address bar.  (The tag folder holds all of the tags and their individual tag pages.)  So, if I try to type in katiebui.com/tag/college, I would get a 404 error.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The tag page generator&#39;s script &lt;i&gt;must&lt;/i&gt; have been working fine, since it was able to generate pages in the local build.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It couldn&#39;t be a DNS problem because the 404 error was from GitHub, which means the DNS server pointed to the right guy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finally realized the issue (Ruby plugins aren’t supported), I had the urge to abandon all the fixes I had made and to just get a more flexible webhost than GitHub Pages.  But I fought on when I realized I’d be taking out ~$40/year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What I had to do&lt;/b&gt; was create a directory &lt;i&gt;outside&lt;/i&gt; my GitHub repository’s local directory, and create a script that copied generated files built in the former directory into the latter directory.  (Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/jekyll-plugins-github/&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I arranged my website to be like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;website
    |___ everything-master
	    |___ index.html
	    |___ journal.html
	    |___ ...
    |___ ti-lun.github.io
	    |___ anything that everything-master generates
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I placed a Rakefile in everything-master that basically builds everything needed, then empties my local GitHub repository, and then copies stuff from everything-master into it.  Git add, commit and push and huzzah I’m done!… right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Still some problems, but not Jekyll-related&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I’ve noticed is that my domain, katiebui.com, is down at seemingly-random times.  I’d have to manually go to GoDaddy.com and reconnect my domain to my GitHub Pages website, which is annoying especially in the early development phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that it has to do with DNS stuff.  I don’t know exactly how it works, though… (sigh)  Time to either call GoDaddy, or do some experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I think I’ve gained confidence in using my resources (i.e. other people’s stuff) and finding ways to use them (i.e. other people’s advice and experience).  Most of all… I think I learned that reading documentation and restraining my momentary impatience would have saved me quite a bit of trouble, hahaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update!&lt;/b&gt;  I called GoDaddy; they said I didn’t delete the A record of their default parked page, LOL.  Works great now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 02:23:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>katiebui.com/2015/12/30/finally-finished.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">katiebui.com/2015/12/30/finally-finished.html</guid>
        
        <category>webstuff</category>
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
        <category>announcements</category>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>setup</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Growing Up -- An Essay about the Construction of &quot;Family&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has known me long enough knows that my parents and I really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;, don&amp;#8217;t get along&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;  Anyone who&amp;#8217;s been with me since high school knows for sure that in particular, my relationship with my psychotic mother is the cause of a lot of problems that our family has had, and I have lacked a lot of &amp;#8220;normal experiences&amp;#8221; that other children had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Psychotic&amp;#8221;?  &lt;em&gt;Katie, that&amp;#8217;s a bit extreme, isn&amp;#8217;t it?&lt;/em&gt;  No, I really do mean &amp;#8220;psychotic&amp;#8221; in the sense that my mother has these delusions of what life is like and overreacts emotionally to these delusions.  For instance: my dad tells my mom, &amp;#8220;Hey, wait!!  Close the door, close the door, you&amp;#8217;re letting all the cold air in!!&amp;#8221;&amp;#8211;and suddenly my mom believes that she&amp;#8217;s being persecuted and abused.  Having grown up in her cage and having escaped it, I can safely say that my mother is mentally ill in some manner and is toxic for the people she&amp;#8217;s living with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike a lot of my past blog posts (bosts?  lol), I&amp;#8217;m not going to give a lengthy, detailed account of my Thanksgiving break just to prove a singular point: my &amp;#8220;family&amp;#8221; is shitty.  Instead, I&amp;#8217;m going to give a voice to the thought that&amp;#8217;s been lingering in my head, meant to rouse me from the rut that I&amp;#8217;ve fallen in for past couple of weeks: &lt;strong&gt;grow up&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-272&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had just finished watching &lt;em&gt;Bojack Horseman&lt;/em&gt;, a great cartoon that thinly veils strong criticism and commentary on American society with stoner humor and black humor.  If you haven&amp;#8217;t watched it yet and you don&amp;#8217;t give two shits about propriety, you&amp;#8217;ve gotta watch this show!  The premise is that a washed-up middle-aged actor, eponymous of the show, struggles to deal with his self-esteem after starring in a popular 90&amp;#8217;s family sitcom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout some of the episodes, the concept of &amp;#8220;family&amp;#8221; is challenged and morphed by the characters in the show.  There&amp;#8217;s the&amp;#8221;family&amp;#8221; in the sitcom that Bojack and other characters created, made of a surrogate father and three orphans.  There&amp;#8217;s the &amp;#8220;family&amp;#8221; that the director of the sitcom, Herb Kazzaz, told the cast to maintain even outside of the show, if only because showbiz is hard.  There&amp;#8217;s Charlotte&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;family&amp;#8221; that looks great on the outside, but is threatened by Bojack&amp;#8217;s presence; Charlotte finds herself more attracted to Bojack than her husband, and Charlotte&amp;#8217;s daughter finds herself attracted to having sex with Bojack because she finds herself treated like a child with everyone else (especially her &amp;#8220;family&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these examples show that a lot of people try to &amp;#8220;play house,&amp;#8221; try to construct a pretty family, and try to put the pieces together so that their ideal thing of &amp;#8220;family&amp;#8221; is accomplished.*  I really do mean the word &amp;#8220;construct&amp;#8221; because there&amp;#8217;s definitely artifice here.  The funny thing is, &lt;em&gt;so many people&lt;/em&gt; try so hard to construct a family.  Eventually they dedicate so much of their lives to it that it&amp;#8217;s all they really have in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents and I fight every time I come home for the holidays.  It amazes me that this time around, I didn&amp;#8217;t cry on the first two days of getting back (I did a little bit on the third).  But it amazes me &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; that, for some reason, we keep investing hundreds of dollars to fly me home for the holidays.  On one day we have an argument; the next we&amp;#8217;re discussing airline flights back to San Jose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after my mom burst in the door to angrily yell at me having not packed up yet, to instigate a debate, and to leave everyone in a sour mood, I realized that there was &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to come back home for.  For one, it makes answering to people who ask, &amp;#8220;How was your holiday?&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;really awkward.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In seriousness, though, the internet connection here is awful, I eat vegan so it&amp;#8217;s not like I&amp;#8217;m coming home to &amp;#8220;Mom&amp;#8217;s cooking,&amp;#8221; my parents have no hobbies and are incapable of holding a conversation that isn&amp;#8217;t about money with me, and we disagree on enough things that we get riled up about it.**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told my dad to get a refund for the tickets back home during Christmas.  Judging from his reaction, I think he didn&amp;#8217;t take me seriously at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me:  Hey, can you get a refund for the tickets back home?  I&amp;#8217;ve got a place to stay for winter break, so there&amp;#8217;s no need to worry about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dad:  Well, ha, but it&amp;#8217;s winter vacation.  You might as well go back home, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me:  Haha, Dad, being here is no &amp;#8220;vacation.&amp;#8221;  Trust me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dad:  But you come back for family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me:  You guys&amp;#8230; you guys try &lt;em&gt;so hard&lt;/em&gt; to uphold this thing you keep calling a &amp;#8220;family.&amp;#8221;  Show it to me.  Where is it?  What kind of family is like this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; Then my dad goes off into complaining about my mom&amp;#8217;s neurosis and tendency to blow up at any little thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that happen in my family suddenly make a lot of sense to me now.  I mean, I knew it earlier, but now I see it clearly enough to be a rotating gear, a mechanical force that has been churning away long enough to be traceable and understandable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents are an extreme version of the American dream.  (&amp;#8220;Extreme American dream.&amp;#8221;  lol.)  They came from Vietnam with little, worked their tails off to buy five houses, sent their kid to college without government loans, drove dream cars, wore overpriced jewelry that could have paid for my college expenses anyway, and ate gigantic, expensive meals of tiny courses.  I think the pinnacle of this is when my mom bought &lt;a href=&quot;http://s4.postimg.org/uzb70k0ql/Photo_by_Bengt_Enrique.jpg&quot;&gt;these shoes&lt;/a&gt; for about $1200 and never, ever wore them.  When I asked why she bought them, she said, &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t know!  I just had so much money to spend!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet they are pretty unhappy and irritable.  I know this, because they&amp;#8217;re in their late 50&amp;#8217;s/early 60&amp;#8217;s (not that old) and yet they&amp;#8217;re blaming everything on their age, and blaming everything on their bosses, on their children, on lawyers, on everyone except themselves.  And many notions of change or individuality either provoke some unwarranted comment from them&amp;#8211;today I wore a snood and my dad said pointedly, &amp;#8220;That&amp;#8217;s way too thick for your neck&amp;#8221; with a grimace&amp;#8211;or sends them into a rage because they&amp;#8217;ve been bottling up their insecurities.  Last &amp;#8220;break,&amp;#8221; I told my mom that we shouldn&amp;#8217;t buy a fifth house because we&amp;#8217;re already very deep in debt and she began screaming and accusing me of questioning her authority and leadership in the family.***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they are insecure.  My mom, who looks pretty good for her age, still asks me, &amp;#8220;Is it okay if I wear this top?  Is it too young for me?  Will people think I&amp;#8217;m weird?  No, I&amp;#8217;m too old, right?&amp;#8221; with a sense of urgency and self-consciousness that&amp;#8217;s a bit worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this surprising at all?  I think it&amp;#8217;s not surprising to people who aren&amp;#8217;t my parents&amp;#8217; children; after all, humans are incredibly flawed and we&amp;#8217;ve got lots of dramas on Netflix that remind us of this over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; difficult to absorb that the sculptors of a sanctuary, that society says (through laws and media and whatnot) I&amp;#8217;m supposed to have, don&amp;#8217;t know that they don&amp;#8217;t know what they&amp;#8217;re doing and have caused near-irreparable damage to themselves and to me.  &amp;#8220;Family&amp;#8221; is &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be where you have a group of people, usually blood-related, who accept your faults and encourage you to grow, and who are people you can open up your emotions to and get help or help others.  At least, that&amp;#8217;s how &lt;em&gt;Full House&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Brady Bunch&lt;/em&gt; paints it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think that&amp;#8217;s great, that&amp;#8217;s really awesome, to have a private spot on Earth where you can just be yourself and not worry about the transience of that love and nurturing.  But I think people just watch these television families, fall in love with the consequences of what makes a great family great, and then build their own with paper mache and not warm flesh and blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &amp;#8220;consequences,&amp;#8221; I mean the grand holidays, the exchange of gifts, the nicknames, the hugs and kisses&amp;#8230; I mean, affection.  People crave to be loved and comforted so that they can rest and feel at peace, but they perform all these weird rituals of preparing for those events so that they &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; like they&amp;#8217;re loved and comforted instead of actually talking to each other to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; loved and comforted. Then people buy into these rituals so deeply that they are convinced that they are getting what they want, but are denied their true desires so that they end up feeling unsatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong; I think it&amp;#8217;s alright to decorate the Christmas tree, to cut the Thanksgiving turkey and to go trick-or-treating.  But I can&amp;#8217;t be misguided in thinking that we&amp;#8217;ve begun to cheapen these holidays by only craving and interacting with the veneers of them.  Holiday creep anyone??  I think seasonal gift-giving has become something of a spectacle to distract or dispel people from their thoughts that others don&amp;#8217;t remember or think much about them in usual day-to-day life.  It&amp;#8217;s become a mechanical vestige of what used to result from people caring about one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s so weird and funny to see how everything eventually boils down to people wanted to be loved and comforted since day one (their birth).  We are all gigantic children, wearing different customs and hats to try achieve this goal.  For example, academics might use esoteric vernacular, or at the very least, more crafted and elegant diction to sound intelligent so that they are accepted in their communities.  (&amp;lt;&amp;#8211; See what I did there?)  Sasha Strauss, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HPnhg2YolHc&quot;&gt;in this brilliant video&lt;/a&gt;, says that brands like Nike, Apple, etc. are basically like people begging to be loved and recognized.  They&amp;#8217;re masked with logos and corporations but their &amp;#8220;strategies&amp;#8221; all aim to be adored by the masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to the title of this post:  what does it mean to &amp;#8220;grow up&amp;#8221; (you can add the expletive in there if you want to read the question in my voice) ?   Does it mean &amp;#8220;playing the system&amp;#8221; to get what you want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does it mean recognizing this embarrassing fault in humanity?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To refer to the first point, it&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;not at all&lt;/em&gt; a fault that we are creatures who need love.  I&amp;#8217;m actually pretty sure it&amp;#8217;s what got humans to cooperate and survive in the first place.  There&amp;#8217;s a great concept in &lt;em&gt;Ex Machina&lt;/em&gt; that&amp;#8217;s about how sexuality plays a huge role in what makes humans, human.  A paraphrase from the movie: What would two things do with each other if they weren&amp;#8217;t attracted to one another?  They&amp;#8217;d probably go off on their own things and never procreate or build things together.  And then they&amp;#8217;d eventually die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does it mean eschewing that childish desire to become an adult?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading this makes me think of a lot of villains in our books and TV shows, LOL.  Or tsunderes.  That whole, &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t need them!  I can be on my own!&amp;#8221; act that I&amp;#8217;ve gone through as a teenager.  I eventually learned in college that, actually, life is a lot easier, happier, and productive when you admit to others that you need their help and attention.  Not only do you actually get the love and comfort you need, you also find a lot of joy in fulfilling others&amp;#8217; needs for love and comfort.  This isn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8220;childish&amp;#8221; in a derogatory sense at all!  What is &amp;#8220;childish&amp;#8221; about making life better and happier for everyone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does it mean &amp;#8220;playing the system&amp;#8221; to get what you want?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like this is basically what politics and marketing is about, lmao.  It&amp;#8217;s so centered on &amp;#8220;me, me, me.&amp;#8221;  Even if you fake empathy and kindness, if someone gets close enough to you, it will be evident that you&amp;#8217;re doing it all for yourself.  That you are trying to get what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think ignoring what &amp;#8220;you&amp;#8221; want is growing  up.  I think it&amp;#8217;s seeing that what &amp;#8220;they&amp;#8221; want &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; what &amp;#8220;you&amp;#8221; want that&amp;#8217;s growing  up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you are hungry for love and affection.  Yes, you are feeling lonely.  Yes, you have the tools to do something about it and find comfort.  But take a look at these thoughts&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s all about you, you, you.  What about other people?  They are in pain, too, if not in &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; pain because there might actually be people out to kill and persecute them (e.g. anyone in a war-torn state).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people in pain.  &lt;em&gt;There are people in pain.&lt;/em&gt;  I don&amp;#8217;t need to explain this one, do I?!  Every news channel reminds viewers of how much pain X country is in with their revolution, how much pain Y celebrity is having with a breakup, how much pain Z person suffered through discrimination or hatred.  You know what pain feels and looks like.  In fact, you might be in pain right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you have tools, and you are part of this huge party, or sinking ship, or whatever metaphor you want to use.  You can actually fix something.  You can actually do something.  No, you don&amp;#8217;t need to hide under the table because someone said you should.  No, you don&amp;#8217;t need permission to call out bullshit.  You can help!  You can help!!   And everyone, including you, will love some help!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you help out, or better yet, create opportunities for people to help out, you are loved and comforted.   Have you ever tutored someone, ever?    Have you made lunch for someone, ever?  Have you helped someone out of depression?  It&amp;#8217;s an awesome feeling because that person knows how to smile again.  You don&amp;#8217;t really think about yourself at that point. You might even realize that that&amp;#8217;s all you ever really wanted.  The love and comfort is a just a bonus.  It&amp;#8217;s the idea that you can be happy with someone else&amp;#8217;s happiness that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#8217;t have to rely on the holiday sales, the approving smiles of our co-workers, the high grades and test scores, the slick technological gadgets, the TV show rerun binges, the pitiful reminiscing of childhood memories, the pointless one-night stands, the fake kisses and smiles, the flashy expensive clothing, the towering sculpturesque houses, the addiction to our phones and the Internet, the addiction to our drugs and caffeine, the number of loves and comments on our latest pic on our feeds, the obsessive adoration for clothing and food brands, or the disordered goals of extreme weight loss to make you happy.  Some of them are just bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think realizing this is growing up.  I think realizing that our happiness is strongly affected by something as powerful as another human&amp;#8217;s happiness, and not material, surface-level bullshit, is growing  up.  Moreover, to commit to that reality and not some delusional ideal is to grow up.  Done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Really, this show deconstructs a lot of things that people idealize, like fame, love, money, intellectualism, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**I&amp;#8217;m not going to paint myself as a saint or anything, so here goes.  Today I went to the Apple campus store to buy a shirt, which was sort of difficult because so many colors and sizes were sold out.  So my mom verbalized her theory, &amp;#8220;I bet that people from China are buying them in bulk to resell them at a higher price, look, look, look!&amp;#8221;&amp;#8211;&lt;em&gt;while two feet away from a Chinese man making a bulk purchase at the counter.&lt;/em&gt;  I was sick and tired of hearing my mom make these useless, negative generalizations, so I told her on an impulse, &amp;#8220;Mom, can you please just shut up?  I don&amp;#8217;t understand the point you&amp;#8217;re trying to make with those statements.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later out the store, she tried to justify to me that she was &amp;#8220;explaining&amp;#8221; what was happening to me and being informative.  I admonished her, saying that it was really rude for her to say that within earshot.  She said, &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t think he heard it!  I really don&amp;#8217;t think so!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad brought this incident up tonight, saying that my mom was upset that I had told her to shut up.  He then added that doing such a thing was absolutely unacceptable to do to parents.  I then said&amp;#8211;yeah, I definitely hit below the belt&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;This is why you can&amp;#8217;t find a job nowadays.  You&amp;#8217;re so old-fashioned.  As far as I can tell, when there&amp;#8217;s bullshit, people call out on it.  That&amp;#8217;s how this generation works.  Every time you and Mom give me a piece of advice, I go out to the world and find that it&amp;#8217;s about 80% wrong.  And I know it hurts, I know it does!  But that&amp;#8217;s how it is&amp;#8211;keep up with the times.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being honest, I&amp;#8217;m actually not sure if telling your parents to shut up is not a &amp;#8220;totally unacceptable&amp;#8221; thing in my generation.  But I think it&amp;#8217;s a necessary thing in &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; case, because I&amp;#8217;ve tried being silent for a portion of my childhood and that didn&amp;#8217;t work out for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***  Now that I see it, I kind of? did similar things to my parents, too.  Maybe suggesting that we not buy a fifth house is an &amp;#8220;unwarranted comment&amp;#8221; to them, though I think investing a couple hundred thousand dollars into a house is something that I, as an adult and eventual heir to my family&amp;#8217;s money, have a right to comment upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t really speak my mind as much anymore, though; I&amp;#8217;m starting to learn that vocalizing my opinions about small things to my parents is going to cause more harm than good for either of us.  But I do mention big things, such as my parents&amp;#8217; fixation on money and their inability to have a conversation that isn&amp;#8217;t about money.  They defend their views, saying that &amp;#8220;everything is money.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>katiebui.com/2015/11/29/growing-up-an-essay-about-the-construction-of-family.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">katiebui.com/2015/11/29/growing-up-an-essay-about-the-construction-of-family.html</guid>
        
        <category>family</category>
        
        <category>love</category>
        
        <category>adulthood</category>
        
        <category>values</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blip</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Blip&amp;#8221; is a funny word.  It was the first word that popped into my head when I registered that I had to put in a title for this post.  It sounds like an onomatopoeia that describes its meaning, a sound that, for a tiny interval of time, pierces the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is what I want this current struggle in me to be like.  Go away soon, please!  It&amp;#8217;s weird that I&amp;#8217;m back to where I was in the beginning of last year, except that I know a lot more now.  Now I&amp;#8217;ve got a bird&amp;#8217;s eye view of what I was struggling with the entire year: values!  Just knowing that has been 90% of the battle.  To be more precise, I was struggling with figuring out what values to adopt.  I was experimenting with many aspects of my life to the extremes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of work (5 hrs/day) vs. nearly no work (3 hrs/week)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being unsocial (just in the dorm room all the time) vs. being social (scheduling lots of hangouts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being very logical vs. being very emotional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being uncommitted (no club activities) vs. throwing everything I&amp;#8217;ve got into a group (TEDxUCIrvine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eating healthily vs. eating unhealthily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of exercise (nearly 5 mi/day) vs. no exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of math/science vs. lots of art/humanities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of money vs. scraping by&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of following directions (teamwork, classwork) vs. lots of inventive creativity (art, idea-making)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the school year, my values started to break down.  I was, subconsciously, trying replacing them with new ones.  And it&amp;#8217;s a painful process because there&amp;#8217;s that little moment when you feel like you aren&amp;#8217;t doing anything and you don&amp;#8217;t believe in anything and you&amp;#8217;re a blank slate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day during this summer so far, I&amp;#8217;ve felt this tension in my chest that I&amp;#8217;m a nobody right now, that I&amp;#8217;ve yet to become useful because I haven&amp;#8217;t been &amp;#8220;born&amp;#8221; yet.  I want to go out and do things.  But I&amp;#8217;m not even sure what things I want to do, let alone &amp;#8220;supposed&amp;#8221; to do.  For once in my life, I&amp;#8217;ve had to find out what I want; I&amp;#8217;ve had to educate myself &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to want&amp;#8211;a thing no one can tell you about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes something that would usually be perceived as &amp;#8220;bad&amp;#8221; would happen to me and I wouldn&amp;#8217;t feel anything.  Those moments make me happy and scared at the same time.  I&amp;#8217;m changing and it&amp;#8217;s possible to change my values (hooray).  On the other hand, where&amp;#8217;s the limit to which I can be complacent and okay with things?  I get scared that I forgot how to have emotions and care about things, to have a passion for something I&amp;#8217;d be willing to fight and die for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I get thrilled sometimes when I unexpectedly leap into a tirade or cry or feel sweet joy.  There &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; some soul within me that isn&amp;#8217;t indifferent to everything.  What usually triggers me are family, friends, how other people emote, etc.  For instance, memories of going to Great America in middle school still light up my heart.  And oddly enough, the pride I get from accomplishing an ICS project is quick and temporary, even if it&amp;#8217;s something that signifies how good I am at something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my &amp;#8220;soul&amp;#8221; reacting and emoting to things is a rudiment of values, perhaps passed down genetically or evolutionarily.  And in response to the world I live in, I develop &amp;#8220;internal values&amp;#8221; that I can&amp;#8217;t even understand or seek out yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;#8217;ve been just living.  I feel these little moments of perceiving these subtle layers of what it&amp;#8217;s like to live that goes beyond what words and images can explain&amp;#8230; it&amp;#8217;s those moments that vibrate in your bones, that feeling that is behind the urge to compel.  I also feel the itch to &amp;#8220;do something more,&amp;#8221; to fulfill my &amp;#8220;potential,&amp;#8221; to not just sit around and enjoy my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since that talk I had with Kevin, I realized that I&amp;#8217;ve been enjoying my life too little.  In high school and the past two years I&amp;#8217;ve felt some strange need to be pressurized all the time, to get things done.  That might be in the form of grades, being &amp;#8220;sufficiently social,&amp;#8221; creating enough artwork, and more.  To relax felt sinful.  To some expect, to not punish myself for relaxing was sinful, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look back at my blog entries from middle school, though, it seems in those days I was content with &amp;#8220;just living.&amp;#8221;  I gleefully recalled, with great detail, everything that happened to me that day, down to line-by-line dialogue of people I wasn&amp;#8217;t even friends with.  All I talked about was stuff that happened to me, getting better at drawing, stuff I coveted, and my emotions towards people (especially frustration).  I wasn&amp;#8217;t obsessed with mastering academic things, nor was I really confused about who I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know what happened but somewhere along the way in high school, I became very paranoid and anxious about everything&amp;#8230; perhaps the influence of my mom.  Perhaps it was the friends I hung out with, a generational thing.  Or, you know, all of that combined.  (I&amp;#8217;m looking through my entries in my old livejournal.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://misatotown.livejournal.com/2010/04/23/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s where a noticeable change in my personality/writing happened.  I still wrote with lots of emoticons in later entries, though.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://misatotown.livejournal.com/2011/11/16/&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is another interesting post on work and values.)  I was also pretty precocious and self-aware for my age, though that fucked me over socially &lt;span class=&quot;wp-smiley wp-emoji wp-emoji-tongue&quot; title=&quot;:P&quot;&gt;:P&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been better at keeping myself sane lately.  I don&amp;#8217;t get as paranoid over things anymore.  Even when I &amp;#8220;try&amp;#8221; to, I think to myself, &amp;#8220;No wait&amp;#8211;this looks too different.  There&amp;#8217;s a lot of nuances that differentiate this experience from the last.&amp;#8221;  Or, I might tell myself, &amp;#8220;No, that took place a couple of weeks ago.  This looks the same, but it&amp;#8217;s actually different.  Things loop; that&amp;#8217;s normal.&amp;#8221;  Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there were themes for my life, it&amp;#8217;d be something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middle school: having fun, making friends, encountering family problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High school:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having to make new friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disappointment/Trying to meet expectations is a HUGE one here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being caught in consumerism/materialism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living with bad parents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living with someone who has mental issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity&amp;#8211;sexuality, body image, intelligence, Summer in the City&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being good at things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First year of college:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living without parents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socializing&amp;#8230; oh JFC THIS one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realizing that there are tacit things that people, who had relatively normal childhoods, expect of you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realizing that I have to choose my own path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obsession with love/savior thing and heartbreak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What a heavy academic load feels like (hint:  shit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Institutionalized school is mostly B.S.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weight gain and dieting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power of logic, math, science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orchestra culture, nerves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to think better, generally (HumCore)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perspective, being really good at thinking like someone else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second year of college:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nihilism and free will&amp;#8230; THIS one oh god&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;#8220;self&amp;#8221; beyond the self&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power of perception and &amp;#8220;framing&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiving my mom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding what love is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Politics and communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The meaning and feeling of giving it all for a team/committed cause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globalism, realizing that the world is huge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complexity in EVERYTHING, especially human emotion.  &amp;#8220;Modules&amp;#8221; within &amp;#8220;functions&amp;#8221; within &amp;#8220;functions&amp;#8221; within&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initiative; understanding that no one will do shit unless you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of experience in relation to theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional control and learned apathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking OUT of materialism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding that I enjoy computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying true friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned more about addiction and perspective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimented with a lot of different values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if I were to predict what next year&amp;#8217;s themes will be, I think they will be&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Falling in love with a person, surrendering fear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Becoming passionate about things, especially computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking leaps of faith and getting good at it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with a LOT of unfamiliar people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shaping and finding my identity and values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempts at leading people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being productive, accepting my moments of non-individuality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love and self-esteem with my self&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t think of any more.  I&amp;#8217;m gonna let life surprise me anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already feel a bit better!  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should write and read my writings more.  I should read more in general&amp;#8230; I can see that I&amp;#8217;m trying to avoid reality by reading lots of fanfiction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>katiebui.com/2015/07/02/blip.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">katiebui.com/2015/07/02/blip.html</guid>
        
        <category>values</category>
        
        <category>goals</category>
        
        <category>predictions</category>
        
        <category>mental-health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
